I am a plant geneticist.
[AI] 我是一名植物遗传学家。
I study genes that make plants resistant to disease
[AI] 我研究使植物抗病的基因
and tolerant of stress.
[AI] 能承受压力。
In recent years.
[AI] 近年来,。
millions of people around the world have come to believe
[AI] 全世界数百万人开始相信
that there's something sinister about genetic modification.
[AI] 基因改造有点邪恶。
Today. I am going to provide a different perspective.
[AI] 今天我将提供一个不同的视角。
First. let me introduce my husband. Raoul.
[AI] 第一让我介绍一下我的丈夫。拉乌尔。
He's an organic farmer.
[AI] 他是个有机农场主。
On his farm. he plants a variety of different crops.
[AI] 在他的农场。他种了各种各样的作物。
This is one of the many ecological farming practices
[AI] 这是许多生态农业实践之一
he uses to keep his farm healthy.
[AI] 他经常保持他的农场健康。
Imagine some of the reactions we get:
[AI] 想象一下我们得到的一些反应：
"Really? An organic farmer and a plant geneticist?
[AI] “真的吗？一个有机农场主和一个植物遗传学家？
Can you agree on anything?"
[AI] 你能同意什么吗？"
Well. we can. and it's not difficult. because we have the same goal.
[AI] 好我们可以。这并不难。因为我们有相同的目标。
We want to help nourish the growing population
[AI] 我们想帮助养活不断增长的人口
without further destroying the environment.
[AI] 不会进一步破坏环境。
I believe this is the greatest challenge of our time.
[AI] 我相信这是我们这个时代最大的挑战。
Now. genetic modification is not new;
[AI] 现在基因改造并不新鲜；
virtually everything we eat has been genetically modified in some manner.
[AI] 事实上，我们吃的每一样东西都经过某种方式的基因改造。
Let me give you a few examples.
[AI] 让我举几个例子。
On the left is an image of the ancient ancestor of modern corn.
[AI] 左边是现代玉米的远古祖先的图像。
You see a single roll of grain that's covered in a hard case.
[AI] 你可以看到一卷谷物，包裹在一个坚硬的箱子里。
Unless you have a hammer.
[AI] 除非你有锤子。
teosinte isn't good for making tortillas.
[AI] Teosite不适合做玉米饼。
Now. take a look at the ancient ancestor of banana.
[AI] 现在看看香蕉的古老祖先吧。
You can see the large seeds.
[AI] 你可以看到大的种子。
And unappetizing brussel sprouts.
[AI] 还有不好吃的布鲁塞尔豆芽。
and eggplant. so beautiful.
[AI] 还有茄子。如此美丽。
Now. to create these varieties.
[AI] 现在创造这些品种。
breeders have used many different genetic techniques over the years.
[AI] 多年来，育种家使用了许多不同的基因技术。
Some of them are quite creative.
[AI] 其中一些很有创意。
like mixing two different species together
[AI] 就像把两种不同的物种混合在一起
using a process called grafting
[AI] 使用一种叫做嫁接的方法
to create this variety that's half tomato and half potato.
[AI] 创造一个一半是西红柿一半是土豆的品种。
Breeders have also used other types of genetic techniques.
[AI] 育种家也使用了其他类型的基因技术。
such as random mutagenesis.
[AI] 如随机突变。
which induces uncharacterized mutations into the plants.
[AI] 导致植物发生非特征性突变。
The rice in the cereal that many of us fed our babies
[AI] 我们许多人喂给婴儿的谷类食物中的大米
was developed using this approach.
[AI] 是使用这种方法开发的。
Now. today. breeders have even more options to choose from.
[AI] 现在今天育种者有更多的选择。
Some of them are extraordinarily precise.
[AI] 其中有些非常精确。
I want to give you a couple examples from my own work.
[AI] 我想给大家举几个我自己作品中的例子。
I work on rice. which is a staple food for more than half the world's people.
[AI] 我做米饭。这是世界上一半以上人口的主食。
Each year. 40 percent of the potential harvest
[AI] 每年。40%的潜在收获
is lost to pest and disease.
[AI] 因为虫害和疾病而消失。
For this reason. farmers plant rice varieties that carry genes for resistance.
[AI] 因此,。农民种植携带抗药性基因的水稻品种。
This approach has been used for nearly 100 years.
[AI] 这种方法已经使用了近100年。
Yet. when I started graduate school.
[AI] 然而当我开始读研究生时。
no one knew what these genes were.
[AI] 没有人知道这些基因是什么。
It wasn't until the 1990s that scientists finally uncovered the genetic basis of resistance.
[AI] 直到20世纪90年代，科学家才最终发现了抗性的基因基础。
In my laboratory. we isolated a gene for immunity to a very serious
[AI] 在我的实验室里。我们分离出一种对一种非常严重的疾病具有免疫力的基因
bacterial disease in Asia and Africa.
[AI] 亚洲和非洲的细菌性疾病。
We found we could engineer the gene into a conventional rice variety
[AI] 我们发现我们可以将这种基因改造成一种传统的水稻品种
that's normally susceptible.
[AI] 这通常是敏感的。
and you can see the two leaves on the bottom here are highly resistant to infection.
[AI] 你可以看到底部的两片叶子对感染有很强的抵抗力。
Now. the same month that my laboratory published
[AI] 现在就在我的实验室出版的同一个月
our discovery on the rice immunity gene.
[AI] 水稻免疫基因的发现。
my friend and colleague Dave Mackill stopped by my office.
[AI] 我的朋友兼同事戴夫·麦基尔（Dave Mackill）路过我的办公室。
He said. "Seventy million rice farmers are having trouble growing rice."
[AI] 他说。“7000万稻农种植水稻遇到困难。”
That's because their fields are flooded.
[AI] 那是因为他们的田地被淹了。
and these rice farmers are living on less than two dollars a day.
[AI] 这些稻农每天的生活费不到两美元。
Although rice grows well in standing water.
[AI] 尽管水稻在静水中长得很好。
most rice varieties will die if they're submerged for more than three days.
[AI] 大多数水稻品种如果浸泡超过三天就会死亡。
Flooding is expected to be increasingly problematic as the climate changes.
[AI] 随着气候变化，洪水问题预计会越来越严重。
He told me that his graduate student Kenong Xu and himself
[AI] 他告诉我他的研究生徐克农和他自己
were studying an ancient variety of rice that had an amazing property.
[AI] 我们正在研究一种具有惊人特性的古老水稻品种。
It could withstand two weeks of complete submergence.
[AI] 它可以承受两周的完全淹没。
He asked if I would be willing to help them isolate this gene.
[AI] 他问我是否愿意帮助他们分离这个基因。
I said yes -- I was very excited. because I knew if we were successful.
[AI] 我说是的，我非常激动。因为我知道如果我们成功了。
we could potentially help millions of farmers grow rice
[AI] 我们有可能帮助数百万农民种植水稻
even when their fields were flooded.
[AI] 甚至在他们的田地被洪水淹没的时候。
Kenong spent 10 years looking for this gene.
[AI] 科农花了10年时间寻找这种基因。
Then one day. he said.
[AI] 然后有一天。他说。
"Come look at this experiment. You've got to see it."
[AI] “来看看这个实验，你一定要看到它。”
I went to the greenhouse and I saw
[AI] 我去了温室，看到了
that the conventional variety that was flooded for 18 days had died.
[AI] 被淹水18天的传统品种已经死亡。
but the rice variety that we had genetically engineered
[AI] 但是我们基因改造的水稻品种
with a new gene we had discovered. called Sub1. was alive.
[AI] 我们发现了一种新基因。称为Sub1。他还活着。
Kenong and I were amazed and excited
[AI] 克农和我都感到惊讶和兴奋
that a single gene could have this dramatic effect.
[AI] 一个单一的基因就能产生如此巨大的效果。
But this is just a greenhouse experiment.
[AI] 但这只是一个温室实验。
Would this work in the field?
[AI] 这在野外行得通吗？
Now. I'm going to show you a four-month time lapse video
[AI] 现在我要给你们看一个四个月的延时录像
taken at the International Rice Research Institute.
[AI] 在国际水稻研究所拍摄。
Breeders there developed a rice variety carrying the Sub1 gene
[AI] 那里的育种家培育出了一种携带Sub1基因的水稻品种
using another genetic technique called precision breeding.
[AI] 使用另一种称为精确育种的基因技术。
On the left. you can see the Sub1 variety.
[AI] 在左边。你可以看到Sub1的变种。
and on the right is the conventional variety.
[AI] 右边是传统的品种。
Both varieties do very well at first.
[AI] 两个品种一开始都做得很好。
but then the field is flooded for 17 days.
[AI] 但随后，田地被淹没了17天。
You can see the Sub1 variety does great.
[AI] 你可以看到Sub1的品种做得很好。
In fact. it produces three and a half times more grain
[AI] 事实上它生产的粮食是原来的三倍半
than the conventional variety.
[AI] 比传统的品种。
I love this video
[AI] 我喜欢这个视频
because it shows the power of plant genetics to help farmers.
[AI] 因为它显示了植物基因对农民的帮助。
Last year. with the help of the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.
[AI] 去年。在比尔和梅林达盖茨基金会的帮助下。
three and a half million farmers grew Sub1 rice.
[AI] 350万农民种植1号以下的水稻。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
Now. many people don't mind genetic modification
[AI] 现在许多人不介意基因改造
when it comes to moving rice genes around.
[AI] 当涉及到水稻基因的转移时。
rice genes in rice plants.
[AI] 水稻植物中的水稻基因。
or even when it comes to mixing species together
[AI] 甚至当涉及到混合物种时
through grafting or random mutagenesis.
[AI] 通过嫁接或随机突变。
But when it comes to taking genes from viruses and bacteria
[AI] 但当涉及到从病毒和细菌中提取基因时
and putting them into plants.
[AI] 把它们放进植物里。
a lot of people say. "Yuck."
[AI] 很多人说。“恶心。”
Why would you do that?
[AI] 你为什么要那样做？
The reason is that sometimes it's the cheapest. safest.
[AI] 原因是有时候它是最便宜的。最安全的。
and most effective technology
[AI] 而且是最有效的技术
for enhancing food security and advancing sustainable agriculture.
[AI] 加强粮食安全和推进可持续农业。
I'm going to give you three examples.
[AI] 我将给你们三个例子。
First. take a look at papaya. It's delicious. right?
[AI] 第一看看木瓜。很好吃。正当
But now. look at this papaya.
[AI] 但是现在。看看这个木瓜。
This papaya is infected with papaya ringspot virus.
[AI] 这只番木瓜感染了番木瓜环斑病毒。
In the 1950s. this virus nearly wiped out the entire production of papaya on the island of Oahu in Hawaii.
[AI] 20世纪50年代。这种病毒几乎摧毁了夏威夷瓦胡岛木瓜的全部生产。
Many people thought that the Hawaiian papaya was doomed.
[AI] 许多人认为夏威夷木瓜是命中注定的。
but then. a local Hawaiian.
[AI] 但是后来。当地的夏威夷人。
a plant pathologist named Dennis Gonsalves.
[AI] 一位名叫丹尼斯·冈萨尔维斯的植物病理学家。
decided to try to fight this disease using genetic engineering.
[AI] 决定尝试用基因工程来对抗这种疾病。
He took a snippet of viral DNA and he inserted it
[AI] 他提取了一段病毒DNA并插入其中
into the papaya genome.
[AI] 进入番木瓜基因组。
This is kind of like a human getting a vaccination.
[AI] 这有点像人类接种疫苗。
Now. take a look at his field trial.
[AI] 现在看看他的现场试验。
You can see the genetically engineered papaya in the center.
[AI] 你可以在中心看到转基因木瓜。
It's immune to infection.
[AI] 它对感染有免疫力。
The conventional papaya around the outside is severely infected with the virus.
[AI] 外面的传统木瓜严重感染了病毒。
Dennis' pioneering work is credited with rescuing the papaya industry.
[AI] 丹尼斯的开创性工作被认为是拯救木瓜产业的功劳。
Today. 20 years later. there's still no other method to control this disease.
[AI] 今天20年后。目前还没有其他方法来控制这种疾病。
There's no organic method. There's no conventional method.
[AI] 没有有机的方法。没有常规的方法。
Eighty percent of Hawaiian papaya is genetically engineered.
[AI] 百分之八十的夏威夷木瓜是转基因的。
Now. some of you may still feel a little queasy about viral genes in your food.
[AI] 现在你们中的一些人可能仍然对食物中的病毒基因感到不安。
but consider this:
[AI] 但是考虑一下：
The genetically engineered papaya carries just a trace amount of the virus.
[AI] 基因工程木瓜只携带微量病毒。
If you bite into an organic or conventional papaya that is infected with the virus.
[AI] 如果你咬了一个感染了病毒的有机或传统木瓜。
you will be chewing on tenfold more viral protein.
[AI] 你将咀嚼10倍以上的病毒蛋白。
Now. take a look at this pest feasting on an eggplant.
[AI] 现在看看这个吃茄子的害虫。
The brown you see is frass.
[AI] 你看到的棕色是弗劳斯。
what comes out the back end of the insect.
[AI] 什么从昆虫的后端出来。
To control this serious pest.
[AI] 控制这种严重的害虫。
which can devastate the entire eggplant crop in Bangladesh.
[AI] 这会毁掉孟加拉国的整个茄子作物。
Bangladeshi farmers spray insecticides two to three times a week.
[AI] 孟加拉国农民每周喷洒杀虫剂两到三次。
sometimes twice a day. when pest pressure is high.
[AI] 有时一天两次。当害虫压力高时。
But we know that some insecticides are very harmful to human health.
[AI] 但是我们知道有些杀虫剂对人类健康非常有害。
especially when farmers and their families
[AI] 尤其是当农民和他们的家庭
cannot afford proper protection. like these children.
[AI] 无法提供适当的保护。像这些孩子。
In less developed countries. it's estimated that 300.000 people
[AI] 在欠发达国家。据估计有30万人
die every year because of insecticide misuse and exposure.
[AI] 每年都因滥用杀虫剂和接触杀虫剂而死亡。
Cornell and Bangladeshi scientists decided to fight this disease
[AI] 康奈尔大学和孟加拉国科学家决定与这种疾病作斗争
using a genetic technique that builds on an organic farming approach.
[AI] 使用基于有机耕作方法的基因技术。
Organic farmers like my husband Raoul spray an insecticide called B.T..
[AI] 像我丈夫拉乌尔这样的有机农民喷洒一种叫做B.T.的杀虫剂。。
which is based on a bacteria.
[AI] 这是基于细菌的。
This pesticide is very specific to caterpillar pests.
[AI] 这种杀虫剂对毛虫害虫非常专一。
and in fact. it's nontoxic to humans. fish and birds.
[AI] 事实上。它对人类无毒。鱼和鸟。
It's less toxic than table salt.
[AI] 它的毒性比食盐小。
But this approach does not work well in Bangladesh.
[AI] 但这种方法在孟加拉国并不奏效。
That's because these insecticide sprays
[AI] 那是因为这些杀虫剂喷雾剂
are difficult to find. they're expensive.
[AI] 很难找到。它们很贵。
and they don't prevent the insect from getting inside the plants.
[AI] 它们也不能阻止昆虫进入植物内部。
In the genetic approach. scientists cut the gene out of the bacteria
[AI] 在遗传方法中。科学家们从细菌中去除了这种基因
and insert it directly into the eggplant genome.
[AI] 并将其直接插入茄子基因组。
Will this work to reduce insecticide sprays in Bangladesh?
[AI] 这将有助于减少孟加拉国的杀虫剂喷洒量吗？
Definitely.
[AI] 肯定
Last season. farmers reported they were able to reduce their insecticide use
[AI] 上一季。农民报告说他们能够减少杀虫剂的使用
by a huge amount. almost down to zero.
[AI] 数量巨大。几乎降到零。
They're able to harvest and replant for the next season.
[AI] 他们能够为下一个季节收割和重新种植。
Now. I've given you a couple examples of how genetic engineering can be used
[AI] 现在我给你们举了几个例子，说明基因工程是如何被应用的
to fight pests and disease
[AI] 防治病虫害
and to reduce the amount of insecticides.
[AI] 以及减少杀虫剂的用量。
My final example is an example
[AI] 我的最后一个例子就是一个例子
where genetic engineering can be used to reduce malnutrition.
[AI] 基因工程可以用来减少营养不良。
In less developed countries.
[AI] 在欠发达国家。
500.000 children go blind every year because of lack of Vitamin A.
[AI] 每年有50万儿童因缺乏维生素A而失明。
More than half will die.
[AI] 超过一半的人将死亡。
For this reason. scientists supported by the Rockefeller Foundation
[AI] 因此,。洛克菲勒基金会资助的科学家
genetically engineered a golden rice
[AI] 转基因金米
to produce beta-carotene. which is the precursor of Vitamin A.
[AI] 产生β-胡萝卜素。它是维生素A的前体。
This is the same pigment that we find in carrots.
[AI] 这是我们在胡萝卜中发现的同一种色素。
Researchers estimate that just one cup of golden rice per day
[AI] 研究人员估计，每天只有一杯金米
will save the lives of thousands of children.
[AI] 将拯救成千上万儿童的生命。
But golden rice is virulently opposed by activists who are against genetic modification.
[AI] 但反对基因改造的活动家强烈反对金大米。
Just last year.
[AI] 就在去年。
activists invaded and destroyed a field trial in the Philippines.
[AI] 激进分子入侵并摧毁了菲律宾的一次实地审判。
When I heard about the destruction.
[AI] 当我听到毁灭的消息时。
I wondered if they knew that they were destroying much more
[AI] 我想知道他们是否知道他们正在摧毁更多的东西
than a scientific research project.
[AI] 而不是一个科学研究项目。
that they were destroying medicines that children desperately needed
[AI] 他们正在销毁儿童急需的药物
to save their sight and their lives.
[AI] 拯救他们的视力和生命。
Some of my friends and family still worry:
[AI] 我的一些朋友和家人仍然担心：
How do you know genes in the food are safe to eat?
[AI] 你怎么知道食物中的基因可以安全食用？
I explained the genetic engineering.
[AI] 我解释了基因工程。
the process of moving genes between species.
[AI] 在物种之间移动基因的过程。
has been used for more than 40 years
[AI] 已经使用了40多年
in wines. in medicine. in plants. in cheeses.
[AI] 在葡萄酒中。在医学方面。在植物中。在奶酪里。
In all that time. there hasn't been a single case of harm to human health or the environment.
[AI] 一直以来。迄今为止，还没有一个案例对人类健康或环境造成危害。
But I say. look. I'm not asking you to believe me.
[AI] 但是我说。看我不是要你相信我。
Science is not a belief system.
[AI] 科学不是一个信仰体系。
My opinion doesn't matter.
[AI] 我的意见无关紧要。
Let's look at the evidence.
[AI] 让我们看看证据。
After 20 years of careful study and rigorous peer review
[AI] 经过20年的仔细研究和严格的同行评审
by thousands of independent scientists.
[AI] 由数千名独立的科学家。
every major scientific organization in the world has concluded
[AI] 世界上每一个主要的科学组织都已经得出结论
that the crops currently on the market are safe to eat
[AI] 目前市场上出售的农作物可以安全食用
and that the process of genetic engineering
[AI] 这就是基因工程的过程
is no more risky than older methods of genetic modification.
[AI] 它的风险并不比旧的基因改造方法高。
These are precisely the same organizations that most of us trust
[AI] 这些正是我们大多数人信任的组织
when it comes to other important scientific issues
[AI] 当涉及到其他重要的科学问题时
such as global climate change or the safety of vaccines.
[AI] 比如全球气候变化或者疫苗的安全性。
Raoul and I believe that. instead of worrying about the genes in our food.
[AI] 拉乌尔和我相信这一点。而不是担心我们食物中的基因。
we must focus on how we can help children grow up healthy.
[AI] 我们必须关注如何帮助儿童健康成长。
We must ask if farmers in rural communities can thrive.
[AI] 我们必须问问农村社区的农民是否能够茁壮成长。
and if everyone can afford the food.
[AI] 如果每个人都能买得起食物。
We must try to minimize environmental degradation.
[AI] 我们必须尽量减少环境退化。
What scares me most about the loud arguments and misinformation about plant genetics
[AI] 关于植物遗传学的激烈争论和错误信息最让我害怕的是什么
is that the poorest people who most need the technology
[AI] 这是最需要技术的最贫穷的人吗
may be denied access because of the vague fears and prejudices of those who have enough to eat.
[AI] 可能因为那些有足够食物的人的模糊恐惧和偏见而被拒绝进入。
We have a huge challenge in front of us.
[AI] 我们面临着巨大的挑战。
Let's celebrate scientific innovation and use it.
[AI] 让我们庆祝并利用科学创新。
It's our responsibility
[AI] 这是我们的责任
to do everything we can to help alleviate human suffering
[AI] 尽我们所能帮助减轻人类痛苦
and safeguard the environment.
[AI] 保护环境。
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
Chris Anderson: Powerfully argued.
[AI] 克里斯·安德森：有力地争辩。
The people who argue against GMOs.
[AI] 反对转基因生物的人。
as I understand it. the core piece comes from two things.
[AI] 据我所知。核心部分来自两个方面。
One. complexity and unintended consequence.
[AI] 一复杂性和意外后果。
Nature is this incredibly complex machine.
[AI] 大自然就是这台极其复杂的机器。
If we put out these brand new genes that we've created.
[AI] 如果我们把这些我们创造出来的全新基因放出来。
that haven't been challenged by years of evolution.
[AI] 这并没有受到多年进化的挑战。
and they started mixing up with the rest of what's going on.
[AI] 他们开始和其他的事情混在一起。
couldn't that trigger some kind of cataclysm or problem.
[AI] 难道这不会引发某种灾难或问题吗。
especially when you add in the commercial incentive
[AI] 特别是当你加入商业激励时
that some companies have to put them out there?
[AI] 一些公司不得不把它们放在那里？
The fear is that those incentives
[AI] 令人担忧的是，这些激励措施
mean that the decision is not made on purely scientific grounds.
[AI] 这意味着决策不是基于纯粹的科学依据。
and even if it was. that there would be unintended consequences.
[AI] 即使是这样。会有意料之外的后果。
How do we know that there isn't a big risk of some unintended consequence?
[AI] 我们怎么知道没有发生意外后果的大风险？
Often our tinkerings with nature do lead to big. unintended consequences
[AI] 我们对大自然的修修补补常常会导致巨大的灾难。意外后果
and chain reactions.
[AI] 以及连锁反应。
Pamela Ronald: Okay. so on the commercial aspects.
[AI] 帕梅拉·罗纳德：好的。商业方面也是如此。
one thing that's really important to understand is that.
[AI] 有一点非常重要，那就是要理解。
in the developed world. farmers in the United States.
[AI] 在发达国家。美国的农民。
almost all farmers. whether they're organic or conventional.
[AI] 几乎所有的农民。不管是有机的还是传统的。
they buy seed produced by seed companies.
[AI] 他们购买种子公司生产的种子。
So there's definitely a commercial interest to sell a lot of seed.
[AI] 所以出售大量种子肯定有商业利益。
but hopefully they're selling seed that the farmers want to buy.
[AI] 但希望他们卖的是农民想买的种子。
It's different in the less developed world.
[AI] 这在欠发达国家是不同的。
Farmers there cannot afford the seed.
[AI] 那里的农民买不起种子。
These seeds are not being sold.
[AI] 这些种子没有出售。
These seeds are being distributed freely through traditional kinds of certification groups.
[AI] 这些种子通过传统的认证团体自由分发。
so it is very important in less developed countries
[AI] 因此，这在欠发达国家非常重要
that the seed be freely available.
[AI] 种子可以免费获得。
CA: Wouldn't some activists say that this is actually part of the conspiracy?
[AI] CA：难道一些活动人士不会说这实际上是阴谋的一部分吗？
This is the heroin strategy.
[AI] 这就是海洛因策略。
You seed the stuff. and people have no choice
[AI] 你播下种子。人们别无选择
but to be hooked on these seeds forever?
[AI] 但是永远被这些种子所吸引？
PR: There are a lot of conspiracy theories for sure. but it doesn't work that way.
[AI] 公关：有很多阴谋论是肯定的。但不是这样的。
For example. the seed that's being distributed. the flood-tolerant rice.
[AI] 例如正在分发的种子。耐洪水的水稻。
this is distributed freely
[AI] 这是免费分发的
through Indian and Bangladeshi seed certification agencies.
[AI] 通过印度和孟加拉国种子认证机构。
so there's no commercial interest at all.
[AI] 所以根本没有商业利益。
The golden rice was developed through support of the Rockefeller Foundation.
[AI] 金稻是通过洛克菲勒基金会的支持而发展起来的。
Again. it's being freely distributed.
[AI] 再一次它正在免费分发。
There are no commercial profits in this situation.
[AI] 在这种情况下没有商业利润。
And now to address your other question about. well. mixing genes.
[AI] 现在来回答你的另一个问题。好混合基因。
aren't there some unintended consequences?
[AI] 难道没有一些意想不到的后果吗？
Absolutely -- every time we do something different.
[AI] 当然，每次我们做不同的事情。
there's an unintended consequence.
[AI] 这是一个意想不到的后果。
but one of the points I was trying to make
[AI] 但我想说的一点是
is that we've been doing kind of crazy things to our plants.
[AI] 我们一直在对我们的工厂做一些疯狂的事情。
mutagenesis using radiation or chemical mutagenesis.
[AI] 使用辐射或化学诱变的诱变。
This induces thousands of uncharacterized mutations.
[AI] 这导致了成千上万的非特征突变。
and this is even a higher risk of unintended consequence
[AI] 这是一个更高的意外后果风险
than many of the modern methods.
[AI] 比许多现代方法都好。
And so it's really important not to use the term GMO
[AI] 因此，不使用“转基因”一词非常重要
because it's scientifically meaningless.
[AI] 因为它在科学上毫无意义。
I feel it's very important to talk about a specific crop
[AI] 我觉得谈论一种特定的作物非常重要
and a specific product. and think about the needs of the consumer.
[AI] 和特定的产品。并考虑消费者的需求。
CA: So part of what's happening here is that there's a mental model
[AI] CA:所以这里发生的部分事情是有一个心理模型
in a lot of people that nature is nature. and it's pure and pristine.
[AI] 在很多人看来，自然就是自然。它是纯净的，原始的。
and to tinker with it is Frankensteinian.
[AI] 修补它是科学怪人。
It's making something that's pure dangerous in some way.
[AI] 它在制造一些在某种程度上纯粹危险的东西。
and I think you're saying that that whole model
[AI] 我想你是说整个模型
just misunderstands how nature is.
[AI] 只是误解了自然是怎样的。
Nature is a much more chaotic interplay of genetic changes
[AI] 自然界是基因变化的一个更加混乱的相互作用
that have been happening all the time anyway.
[AI] 无论如何，这种情况一直在发生。
PR: That's absolutely true. and there's no such thing as pure food.
[AI] 公关：这是绝对正确的。没有纯食物这回事。
I mean. you could not spray eggplant with insecticides
[AI] 我是说。你不能用杀虫剂喷洒茄子
or not genetically engineer it. but then you'd be stuck eating frass.
[AI] 或者不是基因工程。但你会被困在吃弗劳斯。
So there's no purity there.
[AI] 所以这里没有纯度。
CA: Pam Ronald. thank you.  That was powerfully argued.
[AI] CA:帕姆·罗纳德。非常感谢。这是强有力的辩论。
PR: Thank you very much. I appreciate it.
[AI] 公关：非常感谢。我很感激。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）